Yeah, let's get into it. Right, Gaza.
So, the news the news was uh all day
long this very bleak
>> um assessment of what was about to
happen. Netanyahu's war cabinet voted
yesterday, as expected, to authorize the
IDF to go in and occupy all of Gaza,
including Gaza City, which is sort of
the last redout of where civilians can
still live sort of uh in the rubble.
>> The question was, what's going to happen
to the hostages and the Gazins when this
happens? And basically, the assessment
was the hostages are all going to be
killed. and a lot more Gazins are going
to die unnecessarily and the genocide is
going to accelerate. This whole thing
really appalled the international
community and uh now you've seen a huge
reaction. Germany said announced that it
was going to stop transfer of weapons to
Israel. Germany is of course a very
tight ally
>> ever mostly due to the guilt from World
War II and the Holocaust. um kind of
understandably uh but it's also kind of
stupid in some ways. But that's you know
we can leave that for another time
maybe. But anyway, John, you informed me
just as we were about to go on the air
that there's been some break late
breaking developments here.
>> Yeah. Yeah, Benjamin Netanyahu announced
just in the last 20 minutes or so that
there has been such an international
outcry and there has been such strong
international pressure on the Israelis
for taking this stupid decision to to
occupy Gaza City that they have just
canled the plan. They're not going to
invade and occupy Gaza City. Now, that
doesn't really change anything. Like you
said, Ted, people are just living in the
rubble. literally living in rubble
probably with many thousands of dead
bodies under there that haven't yet been
counted. But this is really the first
time that the Israelis have responded to
largecale international pressure since
this thing started. It's the first time.
So, I hope that uh that these countries,
and they're mostly Western countries
because everybody else already supports
the Palestinians, but the Western
countries, I hope, will keep this up
because uh it might be the only thing to
save some Palestinian lives.
>> Um so, yeah, finally the Israelis are
feeling the heat. They seemed
impervious.
>> Yeah, very much so.
>> So, I guess now the question is what
next? I mean, you know, Okay, so
>> can't trust them.
>> No. Well, that's that's that's clearly
true. Um, I guess the question now is
though, okay, so if the Israelis aren't
going to do that, I mean, the status quo
isn't access isn't acceptable really for
anyone, right? It's not certainly not
acceptable for the Palestinians who live
there. And it's not really from the
standpoint of the Israelis acceptable
either. Uh, they don't want to leave
Hamas in charge. uh they don't want to
understandably I think yeah the
Palestinian Authority isn't viable for a
variety of reasons uh Israelis won't
accept them but that's fine the
Palestinians won't accept them either so
it's like now the we are sort of we're
back at square one right is does this
mean Germany's going to resume arms
shipments by the way
>> I would suspect yes that they would
resume arm shipments you remember the
Germans more than any other western
country have this policy fueled by guilt
by national guilt over the Holocaust.
And now they're bending over backwards
and practically fighting with the Greeks
to see which country can be the most
pro-Israel. Greece is starting to see
some upheaval, largecale
uh uh demonstrations against the
government for its support for Israel.
Uh we've already seen pictures and video
of Israeli cruise ships docking, for
example, at my ancestral island of roads
and Israeli tourists not being able to
get off the the boats because so many
Greek protesters have turned out to tell
them to get the hell off our island that
we didn't want Israeli tourists because
of the way they treat Palestinians. It's
getting to the point where the the the
government, the Mitsutakis government is
going to have to decide if they're going
to be on the side of human rights or are
they going to be s on the side of, you
know, splitting the oil wealth in the
Eastern Mediterranean with the Israelis.
And so far, they're choosing the money.
So, we'll see. It's getting ugly,
>> but not for much longer. So, Marcel has
a question. What do we think? What was
the line that got crossed? Was it the
effect of all this the string of
countries recognizing Palestine? Well,
you can't you can't possibly ignore
that, right? I mean,
>> that was a big part of it.
>> The French announcement triggered a
whole string u the UK, Canada, so on.
Now, the Germany uh arms transfer
threat. Uh, you know, I mean, there's
been, um, there's been some loud outcry
inside is the Israeli political scene
where people um, you know, generals,
former IDF guys, former Shinbet guys
have all said, "This is a disaster.
We're being cut off. Our country is
going to become an international pariah.
It is." Um, uh, one guy said it's going
to become a leper country. Um, and
basically they're, you know, they're
finally noticing, although,
>> yeah,
>> the protests, John, that have taken
place in Tel Aviv over the last 24 to 48
hours, they're still not about the
Gazins. It's still not about being a
country that commits genocide. It's
still about the safety of the hostages.
I mean, I understand. I'm not saying
they shouldn't care about the hostages
or that it was okay to take them. it
wasn't. Um, but that said, it's all they
care about to the exclusion of all else,
even on the left.
>> Yeah, I think that's exactly right.
There's going to have to be a major
change here. Um, you know, one of the
things, too, you and I were discuss
discussing this very briefly just before
the show started. It's the the Russian
position on Ukraine. It looks like there
may be something of a breakthrough.
Well, there's kind of a side story to
that, too. The Iranian government said
today how how sorely disappointed um the
Iranians have been um over the fact that
the Russians have been all talk when it
comes to support for Iran in the in the
Iran the 12-day Iran Israel war. The
Russians did nothing but say nice words.
That was pretty much it. And so, you
know, we talk about the Western
countries lining up whether it's behind
the Israelis or the Palestinians when
the the Palestinians are supposed to be
feeling this really great Russian
support, Russian, Chinese, Indian, etc.
And they're not. The Russians are
preoccupied with Russian stuff and with
with Ukraine. They're not really doing
anything anywhere else. Well, um, you
know, Iran, let me, uh, introduce you to
former President Assad if you want to
know, uh, what it's like for Russia to
sort of decide to not be so interested
in you in any way.
>> Yeah. Yeah, that's exactly right.
>> I mean, is that legitimate? I mean, does
is Russia is just legitimately
overextended and it's like guys are
going to have to understand?
>> I think so. Do they just not care? Are
they just being [__] Or is it a
little bit of both?
I think that they're overextended, you
know. And I'll tell you the reason why I
I come to that conclusion is that
Assad gets on the plane and flies to to
Moscow. And then the Russians release a
statement meant for Galani saying,
>> "Can we please keep our bases?"
>> Oops.
>> Yeah. And then Galani's like, "No, get
the hell out." And that was it. They're
out. They're out. So they they so
miscalculated because they're
preoccupied with Ukraine clearly. I want
to add too as an aside. Um I had a
friend over uh the last couple of days,
two friends over. One of them is a
former special forces guy and even
though he's almost 60 years old, he is
built like like the rock. Right.
>> Right.
>> And he has friends who are fighting. Do
you remember that uh Ukrainian volunteer
force where Malcolm Nance and a bunch of
other Americans signed up to go fight?
So apparently it's still a thing and
he's got some friends there that are
that are fighting and they sent him a
couple of pictures of North Koreans that
they had killed.
>> And you should see the stuff that these
North Koreans have in their pockets.
It's all propaganda. like they all have
the same exact things saying that
they're fighting for the glory of the
the dear leader and they're they're
going to make North Korea proud. It has
nothing to do with Russia. The the the
issue though is that
that the average Russian is tired of
fighting this war and there just aren't
enough Russians to keep this constant
supply of people going to the front.
Now, the Ukrainians of course are having
the same exact problem,
>> right? Thus, thus the press gangs.
>> Yes, thus the press gangs. And so I
can't help but to think that, you know,
there aren't enough North Koreans in the
pipeline. There certainly aren't enough
Russians in the pipeline. The Ukrainians
are tired.
I think this may be the beginning of the
end of the war.
>> Well, that's Yeah, I mean, I' I've been
dying to talk to you about this, John,
since I read it. Um, it just broke right
before we went on the air. Yeah,
>> Wall Street Journal reported and they've
had consistently reliable reporting on
this matter that uh there's this summit
that's in some reports was supposed to
already have occurred either yesterday
or today. We don't know when it's going
to happen. It might be, you know, it
might be starting right now even as we
speak. But anyway, it's a matter of
hours or days, right? It's not weeks. Uh
Trump's going to meet Putin in person.
I've always thought that was going to be
absolutely essential for anything to get
done. Um and and Trump apparently Putin
has conveyed to Trump not in person yet,
>> right?
>> That I only he's down to to one one
demand. I just want Eastern Ukraine. In
other words, no more desire
um for denazification or that you can't
join NATO. That's apparently no longer
something. And I thought this entire war
was mostly about Ukraine not joining
NATO. So that you would have basically a
hair trigger, you know, uh you have a
couple of drunken border guards uh on
the Russian Ukrainian border mix it up
one night and the next thing you know
it's World War II. Yeah. But that's what
Putin was worried about. I would be if I
were him. Um but he may be willing to
let that go. I mean, and basically he
just wants the uh status quo to, you
know, basically let's let me have the
Donbos and Crimea, which let's face it,
there's no getting them back anyway.
>> Yeah.
>> And I walk away. I I take my ethnic
Russians with me. Uh if you hate Russia,
you're going to view this as basically
it's a Sudatan land sellout.
>> Um you know, and basically that's that's
the deal. I mean, first of all, do you
believe that report? And if so, do you
think it's enough to get a peace deal
across the finish line? And can the
Ukrainians be rolled? So, three
questions.
I I maybe I'm overly optimistic, but I
think that this is the beginning of the
end of the war. I really do. You know
that they the Ukrainians already don't
trust the Trump administration. That
they see that the Democrats are in
disarray just like we see it. and
they're probably not sanguin that that
significant aid is going to pick up
again. Um, sure they've got the Poles
and the and the Germans and the Brits,
but that can't last forever. And other
European countries are already saying
enough. Enough is enough. And so, you
know, there's no among Ukrainians, too,
there's no really deep love of Crimea.
Crimea's only been a part of Ukraine
since 1953. It was a gift
from Kruev who was Ukrainian,
>> right,
>> to Ukrainian SSR,
>> right?
>> And so I think that deep down they don't
don't really care so much.
>> It's symbolic.
>> Yeah, I think so too.
>> Yeah,
>> it's really part Yeah, in my view it was
never should have been part of Ukraine
and um you know in 1991 probably Crimea
should have been returned to Russia uh
when at the time of the split, but
that's not how it went. And um the
Donbos is a little more complicated.
>> Yeah.
>> But but there's e but it's mostly ethnic
Russians who I think mostly want to be
in Russia.
>> You know, it's funny. All the Ukrainians
that I know, all the Ukrainians who are
friends of mine, including my best
friend's wife, are ethnic Russians. And
they hate the fact that there's been
fighting. They hate the fact that
there's been death and destruction, but
they want to be Russian.
They speak Russian at home. They're
members of the Russian Orthodox Church.
They want to be Russian.
And when Russia offered these people the
right to apply for uh Russian passports,
they took them up on it in droves. They
didn't have to. No one's no one's
holding a gun to their head saying come
down to the passport office.
>> That's right. They wanted they wanted to
be and let's not forget that for the
last uh you know for the eight years
prior to the war um the Russian the the
Russian independence forces the you know
represented by the so-called PPRs right
the people's republics um of Dunetskin
Luhansk uh they wanted to uh they've
been they've been fighting and getting
bombed and shelled by the Ukrainians I
mean so it is it was kind of a it was a
separatist movement to begin with. I
mean, this is kind of like it's almost
like the Kurds, right, in Turkey. Sort
of. I think it is. I think it is like
the like the Kurds in Turkey. Uh there
was something else, too. I just saw uh
from Marble 455. Ah, this is the $64,000
question right here. Does the US lift
sanctions if Putin makes a deal with
Trump?
>> That is the question.
>> That's the question. That's what it all
comes down to.
Yeah.
>> Well, and I guess I mean I I'd have to
think that that would be an important
part of the deal for Putin.
>> It would have to be. It would have to be
because we've we've made it just
difficult enough for Russia to sell gas
to the point where we're now threatening
the Indian government with 50% tariffs
if they if they don't stop buying
Russian gas. You know, we're going to
end up having sanctions or tariffs on
practically every country on the world
unless we can get this thing settled.
Plus, John gets his TV show back if the
sanctions are lifted.
>> Right. True.
>> And and I need the money very badly.
>> Yes. Yes, you do. So do I. But I don't,
you know, I don't know. I don't think
the radio's ever coming back, though.
>> No, I don't think so either.
>> Unfortunately.
>> Yes, that's right. It was it was it it
never should have gone away. Um
yeah, so I guess yeah, I I agree with
you. I think that uh I think this is the
beginning of the end. It's a
breakthrough. I think you know what's
going to really if Trump really wants to
get across the line and maybe be a
serious contender for the Peace Prize.
Not that they will ever give it to him.
Um he's going to need to do something he
doesn't like to do. He's going to have
to spend overnight
meeting with with Putin. Um, you know,
probably like four, five nights in a
row.
>> Yeah.
>> And just do nothing else.
>> Where do you think that
>> focus, focus, focus and listen to Putin
talk about, you know, medieval Russian
history for hours on end?
>> Yep.
>> And then they can get there. I think I
think this is about Putin needs to feel
like this guy, he showed up, he's gonna
listen, he's gonna give me what I want,
he's going to be respectful, he's going
to recognize Russia as a great power,
and then we're good.
>> Yeah. Um, where do you think a meeting
like that would take place? It would
have to be in Asia somewhere, right?
>> Yeah. You know, that's that's a good
point. Um, you know, I could see maybe
the Japanese hosting something like that
or Hong Kong
>> or Singapore.
>> Yes,
>> something like that.
>> Just like just like with talks with the
North Koreans, the first was in
Singapore.
>> Yeah, because they, you know, in Qatar
is has been mentioned here, but
doesn't seem like I don't know. I think
that's a look that Trump doesn't want.
>> Yeah, I think that's right. Especially
when he's going to get his new 747 soon.
He could do Paris.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Hungary.
>> True. You could totally do Hungary.
>> It's It's a friendly place for both of
them.
>> It is. It is.
>> That That's That would be a sweet spot.
Off to Budapest.
>> Candace Strike, thank you so much. Thank
you for that generosity.
>> Oh my god. Yeah. Thank you indeed.
>> Thank you. I didn't want to let it go.
And Marble 455 has another good
question. Didn't they fire the Russian
embassy DC Chef?
I'm surprised anybody outside the
diplomatic community knows about that.
That was actually a very big deal. The
Russian embassy brought their own chef
from Russia. Every year in the
diplomatic community, there's a cookoff
and all the embassy chefs compete. This
guy won every single year. And then as
soon as the war broke out, the State
Department announced that they would not
renew his visa. I I was invited to lunch
at the Russian ambassador's residence
with a bunch of other people. It was
like 12 of us, Peter Kousnik and a bunch
of people. And the chef really was that
good. As good as they built him up to be
>> really.
>> And then he was gone like 4 days later
back to Russia. The Russian ambassador
finished his tour I'm going to say in
September.
He's gone and has never been replaced.
So, we have a lot of rebuilding to do in
terms of our relationship with the
Russians.
>> Yeah.
>> I don't know what this question is. By
um what do you mean? Do you think they
want to divide and conquer Russia? Who's
they?
>> If you can just let it let us know.
>> Oh, which chef? Oh, it was the Russian.
The Russian. And he was he would beat
the pants off the the French
year after year after year. And what was
funny, the ambassador told us that most
of what he made was French. It wasn't
even Russian food.
>> Oh, so the clarification from Bosow is
the West. Well, of course, they've
always wanted to.
>> Yeah. Yeah, definitely.
>> I mean, the Ukraine war was part of
that. I mean, God, it's just been an
endless It's been an endless uh series
of attacks ever since the Bolevik
Revolution. Never stopped.
>> Um, the Cold War never ended, you know.
They just never stopped. Uh the Russians
thought that the Cold War was over, but
no one told the US.
>> Ted, four minutes ago,
>> a story broke. Uh
>> oh.
>> That
President Trump has met with the leaders
of Azerbaijan and Armenia
>> this afternoon and they will sign a
joint peace declaration to end four
decades of conflict. So this is Negorno
Carabach.
>> It's Negorno Carabach. And for the first
time, peace is at hand since the
conflict started in 1988.
And they're both lauding the peacemaking
acumen of Donald J. Trump.
How do you like that?
Well, that's great. Now I the way I
remember that working out though wasn't
isn't that kind of like all right so
>> correct so maybe we we need to summarize
what happened here with so yeah so at
the end of the so in 1991 when the
Soviet Union broke apart yeah
>> uh a lot of the borders didn't make a
lot of sense but basically the borders
of the 15 autonomous republics all
became 15 independent nations such as
they were and there ended up with what
they called frozen conflict zones all
for the USSR all over the place like the
Transnistria. There's all sorts of weird
border conflicts that you hear about
like in the Fana Valley and so on in
between Usbekistan, Tajikistan and
Kyrstan. Anyway, one of them was this
Negorno Carabach. Um this is in
Azerbaijan. Right. Right.
>> But it's but they're ethnic Armenian
>> but they're ethnic Armenians. It's like
it's a little island of Armenia inside
Azerbaian. So recently, but correct me
if I'm wrong. Did I I didn't hallucinate
this, right? Like a few years ago,
basically they were ethnically cleansed.
>> Yes.
>> So the basically the A the Azeris went
in,
>> kicked the Armenians asses
>> and kicked them out and and just said,
"Get the [__] out." And they sent them
to Armenia proper. Right. And the
Armenians took the took them in,
although they're not like really the
same kind of Armenians anymore.
>> And they have a funny accent.
>> Yeah. But anyway, so so now Azerbai, so
basically the um the the Armenians lost
>> Yeah.
>> they lost their people. They lost their
ethnic brothers. And so basically, I
guess, isn't this pretty much just
accepting the facts on the ground, much
like Russia and Ukraine?
>> Well, some of our our listeners are
making points here that I think are very
good. EO not sure this is good for
Armenians. Exactly. I'm of exactly the
same mind because the Armenians are are
being forced to operate from a position
of weakness.
>> Um they've already been been beaten.
They've already been ethnically cleansed
and um so I'm not sure what the
Armenians are getting out of this. But
then um oh it uh
>> maybe money.
>> Oh, here it is. The president of Armenia
said Trump deserves the Nobel Peace
Prize. Houdini said it.
>> Really? it. I I mean this is just I I
can't wrap my brain around this. It's
like every day whether it's Congo,
Rwanda, it's it's Cambodia, Thailand,
it's Armenia, Azerbaijan, it's like what
what I mean it's
>> could this actually happen?
>> Yeah, I know. It's like a it's like a
fever dream. Um
>> like a fever dream. Yes. And it's yeah,
it's very strange because this same I
mean Donald Trump is both an ignorant
fascist blowhard and a brilliant
peacekeeping genius at the same time.
Oh, Trump hinted that there might be
possible Somali land peace treaty. I
went to Somaliand in 2011.
There's literally nothing there. It's
just sand and a couple of villages. So
this is nearria, right? This is north
>> in Ethiopia. Uh near Ethiopia. Yeah.
>> It borders Djibouti.
>> And um they just want to be an
independent country. They're happy to
ally themselves with the United States.
They just don't want to be a part of
Somalia because Somalia is a, you know,
it's a a pirate country. Um yeah, and
Obama won his Nobel Peace Prize just
because his name wasn't George W. Bush.
>> That's all he had to do. That was it.
literally he was he he there's no
peacemaking actually that occurred quite
to the contrary right he expanded he
sent more troops to Iraq and Afghanistan
>> kind of taking a page from the Kissinger
playbook
>> like to try to you know we'll make peace
after we accelerate the war
>> QQTF at the bottom here has a good
question um it's about the corridor to
uh not just I I can never say it not
just Javan
>> so do they get the do they get the
corridor
I mean, that's really what they want.
>> The Armenians.
>> Yeah.
>> We don't we don't know anything about
this peace deal. Yeah.
>> This deal just Yeah. There's no details
available.
>> Yeah. We don't we don't know. But that's
really what they need. They need that
corridor.
>> You know, interestingly enough, too, the
Iranians hate the Azeris.
All my Iranian friends when they talk
about Azarbaian, they'll refer to it as
the other Azarbaian because there's an
Iranian state.
>> Azeris are a huge ethnic minority in
Iran. Yeah,
>> huge. And even in in Azerbaijan, one of
the official languages is Farsy.
Yeah. Djibouti. I I was in the I I'll
say some funny thing that that USC XXX
A-Rod 21. Haha. Djibouti. I I was in the
Holiday and Express in
Salt Lake City on Saturday
and I walk in the lobby to check in and
there's this big huge guy there and he
points at me and he says, "Hey,
YouTube CIA guy."
And I said, I said, "Right, right. Nice
to meet you." And I put out my hand and
I shook his hand. And he said he said he
watches my my videos when he's laying in
bed at night, which is funny because I
watch other people's videos while I'm
laying in bed at night. I've never
actually seen one of my videos on on
>> No, I would not. I never read my own
books. I
>> Tik Tok.
>> No, no, no, I don't either.
>> And um he ran back up to his room. He
says, "Stay right here." He runs back up
to his room. He comes back down with a
challenge coin. And it turns out he's
the the American embassy's regional
security officer in Djibouti.
>> Oh. And so we we started ch talking
about Djibouti and he said, you know,
Djibouti is really really
underestimated. It's a little teeny tiny
country. It has only one city
>> called Djibouti.
>> Mhm.
>> And um you know, a couple of villages
here and there. It's very poor, but
we're there militarily. The Chinese are
there military militarily. And the
French Foreign Legion still has a
presence there. It's 16 miles across the
water from Yemen. So everybody's
interested and it's connected to Somalia
on the south to help us fight the
pirates.
>> This is a very important place.
>> Uh as by the way speaking of if for
people who aren't aware I think most of
our viewers are
>> uh Azerbaijan you know is the is why
Hitler invaded the Soviet Union right
people are always like why did why did
something stupid like that? Right. It
was to get the oil fields in Baku.
>> That's exactly right. He was like, "Oh
my god, what am I going to do? I have
this allied oil embargo. Europe,
occupied Europe's not getting any oil.
I've got to get the I've got to get that
Soviet oil." Uh, and then he got started
a month late.
>> And that's what did him in.
>> That's what did him in.
>> Yes. The weather turned.
>> Yeah. And also that the late start,
right, there was a there was some kind
of coup in um in in in the Balkans,
right? Like someone overthrew his Nazi
puppet. I think was it in Serbia,
Croatia?
>> No, it it was in um
Hungary. It it was uh uh Hydrick Central
Europe. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Or Czechoslovakia.
>> It was in Czechoslovakia
>> or maybe
>> but it was one of those. And he was
like, I can't let that pass. I have to
send my army there. And then by the time
he got started, so Azaran's really has a
it was a lynch pin to a hugely
important, you know, uh historical
event. I'm Houdini makes a point too. He
had to go save Mussolini. This is
something that the Greeks are so so
proud of. Um
in October 1940, Mussolini ordered his
prime minister, I'm sorry, ordered his
ambassador to go see the prime minister
of Greece at midnight and he gave um
prime minister um Metakas an ultimatum
to just surrender to the Italians and
that Italy would occupy Greece and he
said oh which means no. So now there's
this national holiday called Oi Day.
It's celebrated both in Greece and in
the United States among Greek Americans.
It's a very very important holiday. So
the Italians attacked Greece the very
next day. And the Greeks not only beat
the Italians back, but the Greeks ended
up occupying the southern third of
Albania. And so Hitler had to send
troops to Greece to bail out the
Italians. and it set back the invasion
of of the Soviet Union to the point
where later
um
uh Churchill said, "Henceforth we will
not say that the Greeks fought like
heroes. We would we will say that heroes
fought like Greeks."
>> And they still quote it.
>> My phrase.
>> Yeah. They still quote it. But but the
Greeks are very proud that that their
steadfastness against the Italians and
then against the Germans delayed the
invasion of the Soviet Union and helped
to win the war in the end.
>> That's no that's that's seriously
incredibly important. All right, so
let's talk about um so what's going to
come out of this uh Russia Ukraine
thing? Obviously
>> I don't know, man. I'm always accused of
being overly optimistic and it's because
I've got like a, you know, financial
stake in this peace this peace deal.
>> Yeah, that's why I'm not optimistic
because I have a financial stake in this
peace deal. Not as big as yours, but
yeah,
>> I want my show back. So, I want my
health insurance back. This Obamacare, I
wish I never heard of Obamacare. Oh my
god. Anyway,
>> it's Yeah, it's all it's evil.
>> By the way, next week, I didn't tell you
yet, John. got a guest coming in to talk
about sanctions.
>> Uh an expert about the effect on
sanctions. Uh you know, it's nothing
that you'd be surprised by, but the
details are very are are really
interesting.
>> Excellent. Excellent.
>> Think we're going to do that Thursday.
>> I have a lot of questions about
sanctions.
>> Yeah, I I know we both care about the
topic a lot. I think sanctions are
ridiculous. I'm not saying they can't
work. They just sort of almost never do.
>> Um I guess is is is my answer to this.
Um let's talk about uh the census. So
>> yeah. Yeah.
>> So
>> this thing's spreading man.
>> Under the US Constitution, the uh Census
Bureau counts the number of people in
the United States every 10 years. Key
word is the people in the United States.
Now, um Donald Trump is has he signed an
executive order. Um by the way, um John,
I don't know. I think we're each going
to get our own personal executive orders
from Trump every day from now on telling
us like what to wear, like you know,
like how we should do our hair, all that
stuff. And anyway, so so he's he's he's
he he's really got, you know, he's he's
very granular this guy. He's like
Turkman Bashi.
Turkman Bashi would sign he like, you
know, that Turkman Bbashi the dictator
uh Sapper Murat Nyazaf of Turk Menistan.
Yeah. was such a personalized dictator
that he literally personally um
considered every college application
>> in saying that
>> all of them
>> absolutely nuts
>> and and he like he was like also he was
like oh people should stop smoking it's
not good for you his doctor made him
stop smoking so he's like okay smoking
is banned that's
>> just like that what was the deal Ted
with why did every car have to be white
>> you know that's a good question although
frankly very Turk menistan might be the
hottest country in the world. So, white
is best.
>> That makes sense.
>> Hot place.
>> Yeah. So, he was he looked like a like a
sort of like a business dude really like
a cheap business dude wearing a cheap
suit. Um yeah. Anyway, so acting like
Turkman Trumpashi is uh wants the mig
all immigrants out of the census, right?
The practical effect of this is, of
course, it's another GOP attack on the
blue states, right? Because they think
that a disproportionately high number of
illegal immigrants live in the on the
coasts. I'm not sure that's really true,
right? But John, isn't the purpose of a
census going back to Roman times? It's
never been about citizenship status. No,
it's always been about trying
>> the number of people,
>> who Yeah. And how many people live here?
what kind of people are they? Um it it I
mean without this information, it seems
to me like it would be just like not
having reliable economic statistics. It
would be hard for demographers inside
the government, inside of business to
make intelligent decisions. I mean about
any number of things. I mean they're
still here whether you count them or
not, right?
>> And they have an economic effect. They
have an effect on crime and a million
other things. Yes. You're just not going
to count them. I mean, it doesn't seem
like a good idea.
>> No, it doesn't seem like a good idea. I
mean, how do you how do you how would an
urban planner, for example,
>> plan public transportation routes if
none of these people
>> exist,
>> right? You just pretend they don't
exist.
>> It's about reality. John, I used to work
for a traffic engineering department
when I was a a young man and um the I
remember like we used to we would time
how fast cars went on the roads and the
idea the ideal is that when you drive
down the road the light turns green when
you get there and you and just as you
arrive, right? That's perfect. It
doesn't of course always work, but like
anyway, that's what you're striving for
as an engineer. And of course, obviously
you have c streets going the other way
that you also want that to happen with.
And then you also have want to give
enough time for pedestrians to cross.
You measure how long it takes a person
to cross the street. You want to make
sure that that they have enough time in
the crosswalk and and so on. Right? So
those are all the the factors that go
into it. But I was fascinated when I got
the job that we were measuring the
actual speed of the cars, not the speed
limit. And I said, well, the speed
limit's 40. Shouldn't the light only
turn green for the people who are going
40? Shouldn't the speeders have to hit
the brakes? And they said, "No." My boss
said, "You, we deal with the reality."
So, the reality in my town was that
people typically went 10 miles an hour
over the speed limit. And we want them
to hit that light on time. We don't want
people slamming on the brakes. That
causes accidents, right? People So,
that's not good. So, in fact, we see um
you know, red light cameras cause a lot
of accidents. People slam on the brakes
and get rear ended.
>> Oh, yeah.
happens all the time there. So anyway,
the point is this is about reality. The
census is about knowing the truth. It's
not about knowing some theoretical
idealized version of the truth. And you
can't even the the the it seems like the
compromised solution was well count them
all but have a separate category for the
illegal migrants. But then the problem
is if you do that, the illegal migrants
aren't going to cooperate with the
census and because they're for fear of
deportation, which certainly is a valid
fear nowadays.
>> Yeah. Like today, some poor guy went to
NIH
for some terrible disease he has. He
made an appointment. They wanted to see
him at NIH. And as soon as he arrived,
ICE was on him and they grabbed him and
took him to some detention center.
>> Jesus Christ.
>> So he's sick. Like sick enough to need
to go to a hospital and now he's in a
detention center. Yeah. Well, he's going
to be in in real trouble.
>> Yeah, he's going to be in real trouble.
Um, we've got a couple of questions,
too. Robbie has passed a couple on to
me. Uh, why don't why don't I move to
Greece? I think about that every single
day. And there's an app I have on my
phone called spatos. It means housecat.
It's the Greek version of realtor.com
every single day. And then my son is
constantly emailing me, "Dad, look at
this. Look at this condo. Dad, look at
this house. Look at the view. Oh my god,
it's right on the water. Yeah, but my
all my kids are here. Everybody who's
important to me is here.
>> The the health care would be free.
That's the only reason I think about it
every day. The healthcare would be free.
>> So,
>> what big boss is saying here is correct.
Um, it is the census data is used
representation in the house proportional
of the population of each state. So this
would deprive Democrats presumably of
some seats. It's a it's an aortionate
unfortunate grab, John. I think about
that, you know, of moving to France. I
look at French real estate all the time.
I mean, as a New Yorker, it's so cheap.
>> Yeah.
>> It's like they're giving it away.
>> For 300 or even 300,000 euros or less,
you can have a beautiful 1820 farmhouse
made of stone in a picturesque village.
I mean,
>> man, I'll tell you, even in Athens,
which is, you know, a a major city, this
six seven million people almost,
>> for 550,000,
you can get a topf floor two-bedroom,
two bath condo where you can practically
reach out and touch the Parthonon.
Seriously,
550 580 maybe. And the prices have
doubled in the past three years because
Russians, Chinese, and Israelis are
buying up all the real estate.
Yeah. No, I mean it's it's Yeah. No,
Europe is better. I mean, I was looking
into the French uh medical system, like
what would happen if I were to move
there, and it's like the it's so it's
eight to see the doctor, whether you go
in for a checkup, a whatever, or an
operation, it's eight every time.
>> That's the way it should be.
>> Yeah. It's And that's No, that's the
shitty version for people like me who
didn't pay into the system,
>> right?
>> So,
>> Right.
>> Yeah.
>> How are the prices in Marseilles?
>> Oh, well, I Marseilles. I didn't check.
I I do like southern France. Um
>> I'm not a Marseilles fan, though.
>> Yeah. I mean, I love Marseilles. I like
the people. They're wild and crazy.
Like, you know what that is? Marseilles
is the New Jersey of France. And I mean
that in the nicest possible way. Uh it's
like these are they're like the they're
like people who are they're scumbags and
they kind of like they own it. Like
yeah, you know this oh nice sofa. Yeah.
It fell off a truck. Whatever.
>> Yeah. That's how they are. And it's
great. You know, they're kind of like
they're awesome people. But Marseilles
say the city it's kind of like you know
like there was that old Huey Lewis song
sometimes bad is bad did a great cover
of it and it's like that's what it's
like it's like you know you're like oh
you see the blinking like La Pigal type
cafe lights and you know the skanky
x-rated stores and you're like oh that's
really charming and it is unless you
actually have to live there. Um, but you
know, I would much rather be up in Exxon
Provence,
>> right?
>> Provence, like, you know, with with the
fl with the flower boxes all over the
place and everything's quaint and, you
know, maybe. Sorry, I'm a little bit of
a of a I might have liked Marseilles
when I was 25, but I'm too old.
>> I'm with you. Uh, somebody just asked a
qu. Any advice on learning Arabic? Force
and Sebastian. Um, yes, I will give you
advice. Don't let it intimidate you. And
here's what here's what I mean by that.
>> When I was studying Arabic in the CIA
language school, my classroom, there
were just three of us in the classroom.
My classroom was next to a uh the
Spanish classroom. And there were six of
them. And the last day that we were in
class before Christmas break, one of the
women from Spanish class came in and she
shouted three, three, three like that.
Meaning on a scale of 0 to five, three
being conversationally fluent. Uh she
had scored three in reading, three in
writing, and three in speaking. And I
said, "Oh my god, we haven't finished
learning the alphabet yet.
So, we started the last week of August.
Here it is the third week of December.
And we had not finished learning the
alphabet.
But then in April, so started in August,
now I'm in April, I had my first dream
in Arabic. And it wasn't gibberish. It
was it was real Arabic. I'll never
forget it.
>> I happened to go to New York to see my
my best friend from college. And um we
got in a cab this the days before Uber.
Fussa is what I studied that first year.
And then um uh Khaliji dialect, the Gulf
dialect.
>> What is Fuss has high standard Arabic.
It's like almost like Shakespearean
English.
>> Like what the Jordanians speak or?
>> No, it's what the Yemenes speak.
>> They speak the purest form of Arabic
>> because Arabic might be the language
with the biggest geographical and
cultural range of any and and from one
from one end of the Arabic speaking
world to the other, they can't
understand a single word the other guy
is saying.
>> But the thing is
>> the writing is all the same and fussa
fussa everybody understands because
that's what you learn in school. They
also understand most people understand
Egyptian and Syrian dialects because all
of the movies are made in Damascus and
all the soap operas are made in Cairo.
So they understand that. But um my you
think my Arabic sounds Egyptian? Um, one
of my professors Egyptian one one of my
uh my teachers was Egyptian. The other
two were um were Lebanese.
>> Oh, that but that's a compliment. Thank
you. I appreciate that. I I never have
trouble getting around Egypt when when I
when I go there. Everybody understands
my Arabic, although they have a funky um
they have a funky accent in in Egypt.
Anyway, um
uh don't get discouraged if you start
learning. Just accept the fact that it's
going to take a long time. It's a very
>> writing is super intimidating for
>> and you know what it's it's not once you
learn the letters. Arabic is very
mathematical in its construct. So once
you train your brain,
for example,
the first word of every sentence is the
verb. So you say, "Went Ted to the store
or visited Ted Montana."
>> Mhm.
>> Once you get used to that, it just it
just all comes naturally.
>> That's what Latin was like.
>> Yeah. Latin's very although the the word
order it doesn't matter at all
>> in Latin but
>> and all the best Arabic singers are
indeed Egyptian kum being probably the
greatest
>> Egyptian traditional Egyptian singing is
amazing and pop is great too.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I love Egypt. I really do. I
love it. Never had a bad experience
there. It's just an incredible place. It
really is.
>> Definitely need to go.
>> Sorry I took us so far off topic. What's
the hardest language to learn? I have no
idea.
>> I can't imagine learning Chinese. I
can't even begin.
>> Did you?
>> Yeah, I took a I took two years of it in
college.
>> Is it just a question of wrote
memorization?
>> Uh, yes, basically. Yeah. I mean, but
it's it's rough. I mean, you know, it's
I think it's also decontextualized like,
you know, with I had no one to speak
speak.
>> Right. Right. Right.
>> And it's just sort of like I couldn't
imagine needing it really. So, it was
like purely in theory. It's just like I
gave up. It was like I'm the kind of
person like if I don't see like you I'm
the kind of person like if I work for
someone, I'll do anything they want if
they explain why. But if I don't
understand what it's for, then I'm just
I can't do it. And even if it's
something that I'm my own boss, if I
don't see the point, I don't do it. I
just like give up. I crap out. I'm
discouraged.
>> People are making so many intelligent
comments here. Nadia Margaret is exactly
right. The grammar in Arabic is easy and
the alphabet is hard. That's why it took
us all those months. But if you can get
the alphabet, you're going to speak
Arabic. Um, and uh, where did I just see
it? Marcel, do a lot of CIA officers
have accents if they learn a language?
Yes. So, how do you deal with it if
you're trying to recruit people? That's
that's a key. That's something that I
think most outsiders don't don't know is
that
you're not going to go into the
terrorist group and pretend to be
Lebanese or Egyptian.
>> You're going to recruit a guy
>> who's already in the terrorist group to
report back to you. So, you're command
of the language so you can deal with
him.
>> You're not going to be exposed. Yeah.
Because there's all those things you
just don't know, right? Like I remember
being fascinated by during World War II,
I read about a an operation where um
basically um I think it was British and
American operatives were dropped off on
the Normandy coast to basically scope
things out in 1942. And um they, you
know, they they they spoke French and
they dressed right and everything was
fine and they went to cafes and they and
you know what did them in? They were
equipped with No, they were equipped
with preWorld War II French Franks. Now,
they were the same exact Franks that
were in circulation because they had no
new money had been printed during the
war, but they were new. They were crisp
and nobody and for three years no one in
France had seen a new a new Frank and s
and suddenly these are like brand new
and that's how they got busted and they
all got killed
>> right Reed um how did CIA officers come
up with an authentic backstory about
their covers? You go to the office of
central cover and they give you the
backstory and then it's up to you to
memorize it. Now, is it a like so like
with Valerie Pla, she actually had a
business, right? Is that necessary? Do
you actually cover business or
>> she was a deep cover officer called a
knock a nonofficial cover officer?
That's that's a whole different world, a
whole different life. That's why I never
encountered Valerie um at headquarters
because they they don't even come into
the building. They're so independent of
everybody else. But um the rest of us
like I remember going to Central Cover
and they gave me a membership card in
the National Trout Fisherman's Club and
I had you know keys to an office in
Indianapolis that did you know I forget
what import export something or other
that they give you a whole life
backstory and it's up to you to know it.
And so when you get stopped and they say
you know who do you represent? You say,
"I represent, you know, Art Vanderlay
import export." They want to know the
number and the number's got to ring
somewhere and somebody has to answer and
say, "Art Vanderlay import export. May I
help you?"
>> Right?
>> That's of course on the on the sixth
floor of the CIA headquarters.
>> But then like so so the so the doesn't
it so the cover can't really be like,
"Oh, I work at Chase at uh JP Morgan
Chase." And of course they call and you
don't work there.
>> No. Unless you're non-official cover
like Valerie, in which case, not only,
yeah, do you work there, you actually
physically work there and you do you do
your eight hours and then after your
eight hours, then you go out and do your
CIA eight hours. That's a freaking hard
job. I mentioned to a couple of weeks
ago, I think um about uh Amarillis Fox
Kennedy, Bobby Kennedy Jr.'s uh
daughter-in-law.
She was a deep cover officer, but her
cover was she was a um an an art
consultant.
So, she would recommend art purchases to
very very wealthy people. Ah, Eric.
Well, anyway, I'll come back to Eric in
a sec. Um, she would make
recommendations to very wealthy people
and she would be the middle person uh in
these art purchases. Eric asks, "Do you
keep the double pay?" No, you give the
whole thing back. And there is a
dedicated office at the Department of
the Treasury
that collects the money that you earned,
which in some cases is four, five, six
times what you're actually earning, and
then they do your taxes for you every
year.
>> Yeah.
>> I had a boss I had a boss whose cover I
had a boss whose cover was blown by
Aldrich Ames. So they had to the the the
phrase they use is they had to bring him
in from the cold. And um
and uh he his cover job had been as the
manager of a mutual fund. And I'm I'm
talking 27 years ago. He's making a
million bucks a year 27 years ago. He
didn't get to keep one cent of it. Not
one cent.
>> Question. Great question. Are you fired
from the CIA if you're fired from your
cover job?
>> No. They'll they'll transfer you into
another division. They'll probably bring
you inside
and then put you in an embassy
somewhere.
>> That's that's very strange.
>> It's hard. Keep it all straight in your
mind.
>> I mean, is that the kind of thing that
might inspire someone to or be make them
more vulnerable to being recruited by a
foreign agency? Without a doubt. get
used to a certain I mean they think
about all I mean I I worked in a bank
and I couldn't help but think about the
hundreds of millions of dollars I was
dealing with every single day and think
you know I just took a little something
for me they wouldn't miss it you know I
mean I think it's just I mean I
obviously here I am I didn't do it
>> oh yeah Ted we used to joke all the time
that every every I don't know six months
or so you get a you get an email from
the director of the CIA. It's to
everybody in the CIA. And it says, "We
have just arrested one of our officers.
He's being prosecuted for misuse of his
CIA credit card. And let this be a
lesson to everybody that you do not try
to steal money from the government, the
people of the United States, you know,
blah blah blah blah blah." And we always
used to say, "Why in the world would you
steal $50 from the CIA?"
>> Right?
>> Now, does that make any kind of sense at
all? I used to say if I'm going to steal
from the CIA, I'm going to steal like
millions,
>> right?
>> So, fast forward to March of 2002.
A colleague and I are in a van. We've
requisitioned from the motorpool.
We have two duffel bags with a million
dollars in cash in each one.
And I said to him, you know that thing
we always say,
you can't help but think about it.
Yeah. No, I remember one time I had this
loan. It was a revolving line of credit,
which means that uh basically it only
came up every 30 days. No one checked
the balance for 30 days. 30 days. $375
million. And the way that banking worked
and still does actually is that New York
is a is the correspondent city for the
United States. So if a bank is like
headquartered in in uh let's say St.
Louis. Okay. So, and you want to wire
money out of the country, it has to go
through New York or LA.
>> Yes, it has to.
>> But if it's in New York, it doesn't have
to go through anything. It's already in
New York. So, if you wanted to wire that
money anywhere to the in the world to a
country that doesn't have an extradition
treaty with the United States, let's
say, you could. And so, I remember just
thinking, gaming it all out. It was like
me and an operations clerk and my boss.
I could get my boss to sign, my boss
would sign anything that I gave him
because he loved me. So just one
operations clerk, you know, a $35,000 a
year operations clerk and me $375
million and it would be gone for 29 days
before they ever knew. And it it it
haunted me. Every day I went to work, I
thought about it. And uh and I was like,
I could have done it. I knew how to do
it. And I was just like, but that's just
no way to live.
to to live. I didn't want to be like
that. Who was that guy who went to um
Robert Vesco who went to
>> Oh, yeah. He ran to the Caribbean.
>> Yeah, he went to Cuba, right?
>> Cuba. That's right. He went to Cuba.
>> I don't want to be I mean, like Cuba is
great, but I don't want to live like
that with a target on my back.
>> Yeah. No, I couldn't do it either. I
couldn't do it. People have so many good
questions. Uh Par uh Paris
>> Robbie behind me, Jay.
>> Paris is asking if uh they have if the
CIA hires people with more unusual
backgrounds. Absolutely. Yes. I've I've
told this quick story before on on my
very first day.
>> Me, they turned me down.
>> Yeah. I I was with uh there were there
were people sitting on either side of me
on my very first day and one uh was a
was a cartoonist and they trained him to
be a a master forger
>> and I could have done that.
>> Yeah, I know. I'm sure that you could
have. And the other was a woman
>> business
for excuse notes
>> and and the the woman on the other side
of me her only her only training was at
the false church Virginia beauty school
and she became a master wig maker for
for uh
>> yeah for operations.
So yeah, they'll they'll take well, we
had a whole cadre of in-house
meteorologists and you know there were a
lot of art people and mutual fund
managers and I mean you name it pilots
>> art are important and yeah graphics are
important.
>> Yeah
>> that is that is a great great question.
>> Yeah that was a good one.
>> All right so let's talk a little bit
about something a little lighter JD
Vance. So, what an idiot.
>> So, Jamie Vance, for people who may not
have followed this story, um he went
he's from my neck of the woods. We both
grew up few miles away from each other
in southwestern Ohio. He claims to be
from Kentucky, but that's a lie.
>> And um he uh he he was on vacation in my
old stomping grounds. My mom and I used
to go to Caesar Creek, which was a
stones throw from Ketaring, where I grew
up. and uh JD and his and his wife and
kids decided to go to Caesar Creek,
which is basically an inland lake. It's
very flat. It's kind of like got one of
those like all over the country, you
know, like the the muddy like beach. The
It's kind of gross actually.
>> Yeah. And
>> we used to swim in our local river uh
Nanet Creek. It was all gross and full
of mud puppies and
>> Yeah. Yeah. It's great. It's not as good
as a Caesar Creek's not as good as a
lake. I mean, as a as a river because at
least a river has moving water.
>> Yeah.
>> Creek's like skanky and just sits like a
flat. Anyway, the point is he was not
pleased with the water level because he
was worried that it might bottom out
because the water's been running low.
So, he arranged with the local
authorities to uh release water from a
dam so that uh you know, he basically
could have his ideal vacation. Now, to
me, this was shades of former New Jersey
Governor Chris Christie. Uh during when
the all the beaches in the state of New
Jersey were closed and Chris Christie um
went decided to take advantage of one of
the closed beaches, he brought his
family uh by him. It was just and uh and
they had the whole beach to themselves
while the whole state is sweltering. You
know, he he gets it to himself. Anyway,
this um this uh enterprising reporter
who's a friend of a friend of mine heard
about it, got a tip, and then with his
editors of permission, got approval to
rent a helicopter to fly over the beach
with the telephoto lens and got that
famous photo of chubby Chris Christie
with his big flabby thighs um hanging
out on the beach with it with his wife
and kids and the and the cooler full of
food and looking like a big pig and so
this now JD Vance has better optics than
that. Well, there are no optics here,
but it really reminded me of that,
right? Like, so if you live in
southwestern Ohio and the water level's
too low and Caesar Creek's gross and
skanky, sucks to be you. But if you're
the vice president of the United States
and the air apparent to MAGA world, as
Trump recently said, then no problem.
We'll we'll do that for you.
>> Absolutely scandalous.
absolutely scandalous. I want to say
real quickly too that a couple of uh
Robbie just sent around um an MSN report
that a that a a US soldier
um Taylor Adam Lee, age 22, has been
arrested and charged with espionage for
offering the Russians plans for the
Abrams M1 A2 tank in exchange for
Russian citizenship. Um, the idiot did
it over the internet and so he was
quickly caught and is now in custody.
>> Uh, and apparently there is an active
shooter
um doing his thing on the campus of
Emory University in Atlanta.
>> That's horrible.
>> Yeah.
>> Never a dull moment.
>> No, never a dull moment is right. And
it's a Friday even. It's usually quiet.
>> Oh, not lately.
>> No.
Um, so well you you want to say anything
about it JD or are we done with him?
>> Yeah, JD, you know, see this is the
thing. This is the kind of stupid
decision that dogs politicians,
>> right? Suck it up. And maybe the bottom
of your canoe is going to scrape on the
rocks,
>> right?
>> Tough luck. That's life. But now he's
going to have to explain himself just
like Ted Stevens had to explain the the
bridge to nowhere or whatever it was. Or
not Ted Stevens. It was uh what's her
face that wanted to be vice president?
Uh
>> Sarah Palin.
>> Sarah Palin. Um you know, you you you do
stupid things and they always come back
uh to to bite you. And I know this
sounds silly and minor, but the knives
are going to come out as soon as the
election near and everybody in the
Republican party is going to want to be
the next Donald Trump.
>> No question.
>> Dumb move.
>> Yeah. I don't think JD has it in the bag
by any means.
>> I don't either. And he's so young. He's
so he could run for president, you know,
35 years from now.
>> That's true. By the way, quick reminder
for people who uh haven't done it yet.
If you can follow us over on Rumble and
watch us over on Rumble at just go to
rumble.comcdprogram
show or just go to Rumble and then just
search for Dprogram with Ted Roll and
John Kuryaku. uh we would greatly
appreciate it because we literally make
like much much much much more money over
there. It's pennies on YouTube on
Rumble. It's dollars. It's really the
difference between uh poverty and um not
poverty. So anyway, just a quick
reminder there um to we'll we'll
probably be adding some ads to the show.
Yeah.
>> Fairly soon, in fact. Um all right. So
yeah, I think that will haunt JD. It'll
come out. it will be used against him
for sure.
>> Yeah, I think so too.
>> Apple's about to uh update their iOS.
Not normally something that's terribly
exciting.
>> However, they're going to do some This
is in the law of unintended
consequences. This is a classic example,
right? They want to um make it so that
you can
uh Oh, bad internet connection in
northwestern Montana.
Oh, well then I'm going to take the
while while Ted is frozen. I'm going to
answer um I'm gonna answer Force and
Sebastian's question about
hypothetically if a person has
information that the CIA would want, how
do you recommend getting it to them? The
CIA has been very weird about stuff like
this. So, what they do is they only
allow the public to deal with uh the
Office of Public Affairs. So, you can go
online and there's contact information
for the Office of Public Affairs. I
would recommend if the if the
information is legitimately sensitive, I
would recommend doing it as a letter, an
old school letter, write it out. Better
yet, type it out. Put your name and
contact information so they can follow
up with you and then just put it in the
mail and send it to them. Much easier
that way. I answered the question. Go
right ahead, Ted.
>> Excellent. I don't really know what
happened there. Uh but whatever. Okay,
so what were we talking about? Oh, so
Trump's so the uh
>> the iOS iOS. So basically, so it's kind
of like if you have Google mail, um they
have a system that if you get like a
spam email that goes into sort of a sub
email inbox in your G in your Google
mail. So going forward, you know how we
all get those spam texts from sometimes
from people we don't know or those spam
risk phone calls on your iPhone uh from
people that you don't know who are
usually spammers and scammers. um you'll
get like um polling requests. I get them
all the time uh by text message. So in
obviously people have been complaining
about that. In a response attempt to
respond to that, Apple says, "Okay, so
we're going to make it so that all of
the the only emails and texts that you
actually see are the ones that are from
people in your contacts." Now, I can see
that being very problematic. I mean, I
do want to get emails from people like
listeners of the T program show. Um, I
want editors to reach out and say, "Ted,
I'd like to hire you for a million
dollars a year. I don't want to not get
that email." That's right. And so, but
the point I would like to just lose the
spam people, but I don't think it's
possible to do one or the other. Anyway,
there's concern about uh among pollsters
who are basically 99% reliant on cell
phones for polling data about politics
and everything else and they say they're
[__] if um if this happens and um they
don't you know they we will no longer
have reliable polling information which
I know there people some people might
not care but I think obviously if you
care about democracy and politics you do
have to care. Polling does matter. Ted,
are you reading Rid's uh comments here?
Just in. Trump's going to meet with
Putin next Friday in Alaska.
>> Oh, at Sarah Palin's house.
>> She can see Putin's backyard from her
house.
>> Yeah. Oh, the mosquitoes this time of
the year. Oh my god, it's going to be
bad.
>> That's true. Well, that's interesting.
>> That is very interesting.
But didn't we say it was probably going
to be in Asia?
I mean, that's about as close as you can
get to Asia and still be in the United
States.
>> So, yeah. I mean, well, I guess this is
kind of
>> Thank you, Marvel.
>> So, this is the US.
>> So, this is kind of like, you know, it's
all about like, well, Trump's going to
be able to say, I got Putin to come to
me.
>> Yeah.
>> And Putin's going to be like, well, it
is a former Russian colony, so
>> Yeah, that's right. That's true.
>> That's true. I'm looking at the
Associated Press now to see what they're
saying. Um, no, they haven't. Uh
they haven't announced yet.
>> We know Do we have a Do we have a
timeline on that?
>> Uh Friday.
>> Oh, okay. Well,
>> yeah. Trump says
>> next Friday.
>> Next Friday.
>> Okay. So, uh is Alaska nice this time of
the year? I mean, you know, it's it's
summer. It's, you know, I haven't been
to Alaska uh really except to change
planes. I I have been to sort of
Alaska-ike places at this time of year,
>> like Labrador.
>> Oh, man. I It was nice.
>> On the first day of summer, the longest
day of the year, I was in uh Iceland. Oh
my god. I mean, it was like noon, 24
hours.
>> Oh, there's that. Yeah.
>> I It It really disrupted my sleep. I I
can't I can't handle that.
>> Yeah, you have to have blackout curtains
for sure.
>> Like everyone's like a vampire.
So, all right. We'll follow that. That's
going to be super cool and interesting.
Um and we'll see if if that's Wall
Street Journal report. it turns out to
be accurate. So, what do you think about
this Apple iOS thing? Um, you know, is
is this a bridge too far? I mean,
>> I think so. I I have my own I have my
own Apple phone set so that the phone
doesn't ring if the number calling me is
not in my contacts. It just goes
straight to voicemail.
>> Figuring if somebody really needs to get
in touch with me and I don't know them,
>> voicemail,
>> they can leave a voicemail and I'll call
them right back.
>> Yeah, fair. Um,
>> but like you,
>> that's what I don't I don't answer any
phone number that's unfamiliar anyway.
>> No, I don't either. I don't either. But
like you, you know, for example, I'll
get my blood work results from the lab.
And the lab's not saved in my phone. And
sometimes they'll just text you from a
four-digit number. I don't know how that
how they do that, but you know, am I not
going to have access to things like that
anymore in this new iOS?
>> Um, I guess not. I don't know. Maybe
those are allowed. Yeah. I mean, yeah.
All sorts of things, right? Like back
when you got a COVID test, it would be
one of those four-digit codes.
>> That's right.
>> Or like FedEx, like your package is on
its way or any number.
>> Exactly. Exactly.
>> Those things,
>> right?
>> Yeah.
>> Right. And I guess unless there's five
more breaking news stories, the last one
I wanted to ask you about is uh Donald
Trump is offering a $50 million bounty
for the president of Venezuela, Nicolas
Muro,
>> right?
>> Um
this to me is a bad look for the United
States. Um you know, I thought it was a
pretty bad look that what we did to
Manuel Noriega. um you know, dragging
him off dragging a head of state into a
a Georgia prison and treating him like a
common criminal.
>> That's right.
>> And uh I think this is even it's even
skankier in a way.
>> Yeah, I agree. I agree. Very unseen
>> practical effect. No one's going to no
one's going to collect the 50 million.
Plus also, who would trust the US?
Didn't what didn't the US welch on like
someone who gave information about Osama
bin Laden? I thought that they did. It
was like or it was someone like that. It
might have been Khaled Shake Muhammad,
but it was one of the big al Qaeda
figures.
>> KSM we paid and Abu Zuba we paid. But
you're right. There was a story about
one of the big figures and we didn't pay
out a dime.
>> And it seemed like we should have paid.
>> Yeah. I don't remember who that was.
>> Yeah, I don't remember either. I'd have
to look it up. My point is I'm not sure
I would trust the US to turn over the
but anyway who's gonna what could you I
don't understand for information leading
to the arrest of Nicolas Maduro. He's
the president. He he lives in the
presidential palace at in Karakas.
>> Yeah.
>> You know where to find him. Go get him.
You don't need to spend 50 cents to find
him. Much less $50 million. I don't even
understand what this is about. They're
acting like he's on the lamb and living
in Tora Bora.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Exactly.
>> You understand this?
>> Like wow. If we only knew where he was.
>> I know. Hey, I should call and get the
50 million.
>> I'll give you his address.
>> Yeah. Right. Yeah. Saddam Hussein, the
the the informant for Saddam Hussein got
nothing. I remember that. But there was
something more recent than that.
>> Yeah.
>> Where we stiffed him.
>> Oh, yeah. Golani had a bounty, too.
>> Yeah. Until he didn't.
>> Yeah. Now he's our our dear trusted
friend for the time being.
>> Yeah. Yeah. That's right.
That's right.
>> Oh yeah. This is This is Is that true?
>> The doctor I'll tell you what
>> doesn't get true doesn't trust
vaccinations because they
>> That's absolutely true. And polio is
surging in Pakistan since then. Um, John
Kerry and I were were going to go to
Pakistan together in 2009 and I said,
"If we go, we've got to get the doctor
out." The doctor was a paid CIA asset.
The CIA walked away from him, and the
guy got life in prison for helping us
find
killed.
>> Yeah. And um, and Carrie didn't want any
part of it. I wrote a long detailed
classified memo about who this doctor
was and exactly what he did and we had
to get him out. Carrie's like, "No, no,
no. We're not doing any of that."
Yeah. Real shame.
>> Well,
>> real shame.
>> So, was it the doctor the 25 million?
>> Seems to be
>> We should have We Yeah, we should have
paid him at least, you know, part of it.
Um,
>> and gotten him out, of course.
>> Yeah, that's right.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Gelani not only doesn't have
a bounty anymore. Just wait until the
big White House dinner in his honor
because you know that's coming.
>> That will happen. Well, once you clean
up and you wear a suit, you know, he
looks like a he looks like a hipster
barkeep in Bushwick
um with that beard.
>> Yeah. Isn't that the truth?
>> So, all right, John, are we
deprogrammed?
Yeah, Ted, I hope you enjoy your weekend
and I hope you have great success at
Barnes & Noble there.
>> Thank you so much. Uh, for anybody who
cares, uh, I'm supposed to be at the I
don't know, I'm not sure I'm going to
show up, but the Barnes & Noble in
Callispel, Montana, 100 p.m. tomorrow,
Eastern uh, central uh, what is it?
Mountain time.
>> Mountain time.
>> That's it. Mountain Oyster time. All
right, guys. Thank you so much for
joining us. Please like, follow, and sh
and share the show. Uh, we'll be back.
uh next week, Monday. I'm not sure about
Wednesday because I'll be traveling.
I'll be not We might have to push that
one back to Thursday, but we're normally
here Monday, Wednesday, Friday, 5:00 p.
p.m. Eastern time. Um please tell all
your friends. Also, uh the following
week, right, we're going to go to
Monday, Tuesday, Wednesday, Thursday,
Friday at 5:00 pm. We're very excited
about that. Hope you guys are too. And
uh really have a great weekend and take
care.
>> Thank you everybody.